
export const ch1mcqs = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "If a matrix M has m rows and n columns, then order of M is__",
    answer: "m-bye-n",
    options: ["n-bye-m", "m<sup>n</sup>", "m-bye-n", "n<sup>m</sup>"],
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question: "If a matrix A has only one row is said to be___.",
    answer: "row matrix",
    options: ["square matrix", "column matrix", "row matrix", "none of these"],
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "If a matrix A has only one column is said to be___.",
    answer: "column matrix",
    options: ["square matrix", "column matrix", "row matrix", "none of these"],
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question:
      "If the number of rows of a matrix M is not equal to the columns of M, then M is___.",
    answer: "Rectangular matrix",
    options: [
      "Square matrix",
      "Rectangular matrix",
      "Symmetric matrix",
      "Identity matrix",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question: "A matrix M is called___, if each of its entries is 0.",
    answer: "null matrix",
    options: [
      "null matrix",
      "Square matrix",
      "Identity matrix",
      "none of these",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question:
      "Changing the rows of a matrix into columns or columns into rows is called___.",
    answer: "transpose of Matrix",
    options: [
      "adjoint of matrix",
      "inverse of matrix",
      "transpose of Matrix",
      "none of these",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "inverse of a matrix A is denoted by",
    answer: "A<sup>-1</sup>",
    options: ["|A|", "A<sub>-1</sub>", "A<sup>t</sup>", "A<sup>-1</sup>"],
  },

  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "transpose of a matrix A is denoted by",
    answer: "A<sup>t</sup>",
    options: ["|A|", "A<sup>t</sup>", "A<sub>-1</sub>", "A<sup>-1</sup>"],
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question:
      "If transpose of a matrix A is equal to A, i.e. A<sup>t</sup> = A, then A is___.",
    answer: "Symmetric matrix",
    options: [
      "square matrix",
      "Skew Symmetric matrix",
      "Symmetric matrix",
      "none of these",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "if A<sup>t</sup> = -A then A is called__.",
    answer: "Skew Symmetric matrix",
    options: [
      "square matrix",
      "Skew Symmetric matrix",
      "Symmetric matrix",
      "none of these",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "If diagonal entries of a matrix A are same then A is___.",
    answer: "scalar matrix",
    options: [
      "diagonal matrix",
      "scalar matrix",
      "symmetric matrix",
      "Skew symmetric matrix",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "If diagonal entries of a matrix A are 1 then A is___.",
    answer: "identity matrix",
    options: [
      "diagonal matrix",
      "scalar matrix",
      "symmetric matrix",
      "identity matrix",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question:
      "If A and B are two matrices then commutative law of addition of matrices is___.",
    answer: "A+B = B+A",
    options: ["A+B = B+C", "A+A = A", "AxB = BxA", "A+B = B+A"],
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question:
      "If A, B, and C are three matrices of same order then associative law under addition is___.",
    answer: "(A+B)+C = A+(B+C)",
    options: [
      "(A+B)+C = A+(B+C)",
      "(A+B)+C = A+B+C",
      "A+B = B+A",
      "none of these",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question:
      "If A and B are two matrices of same order and A+B = A = B+A then matrix B is called___.",
    answer: "additive identity",
    options: ["additive identity", "inverse", "scalar", "none of these"],
  },
  {
    numb: 16,
    question:
      "If A, B are two matrices and A<sup>t</sup>, B<sup>t</sup> are their respective transpose, then___.",
    answer: "(AB)<sup>t</sup> = B<sup>t</sup>A<sup>t</sup>",
    options: [
      "(AB)<sup>t</sup> = BA<sup>t</sup>",
      "(AB)<sup>t</sup> = A<sup>t</sup>B<sup>t</sup>",
      "(AB)<sup>t</sup> = B<sup>t</sup>A<sup>t</sup>",
      "none of these",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 17,
    question:
      "If A is a squre matrix and determinant of A is equal to zero then A is___.",
    answer: "Singular",
    options: ["identity", "Non singular", "symmetric", "Singular"],
  },
  {
    numb: 18,
    question:
      "If A is a squre matrix and determinant of A is not equal to zero then A is___.",
    answer: "non singular",
    options: ["identity", "Non singular", "symmetric", "Singular"],
  },

  {
    numb: 19,
    question:
      "___of a square matrix A is obtained by interchanging the diagonal entries and changing the sign of other entries",
    answer: "adjoint",
    options: ["adjoint", "determinant", "inverse", "none of these"],
  },

  {
    numb: 20,
    question: "Inverse of a identity matrix is___.",
    answer: "identity matrix",
    options: [
      "square matrix",
      "identity matrix",
      "null matrix",
      "rectangular matrix",
    ],
  },
];

export const ch2mcqs = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "The set R is equal to___.",
    answer: "<span>Q ∪ Q<sup>'</sup></span>",
    options: [
      "Q &cap; Q<sup>'</sup>",
      "Q &cup; Q<sup>'</sup>",
      "Q &cap; Z<sup>'</sup>",
      "Z &cup; Q<sup>'</sup>",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question: "For each prime number p, &radic;p is a/an___number.",
    answer: "<span>both B&amp;C</span>",
    options: [
      "rational number",
      "irrational number",
      "real number",
      "both B&C",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "The symbol &forall; means___.",
    answer: "<span>for all</span>",
    options: ["for all", "element", "for element", "is element"],
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Multiplicative identity in real numbers is___.",
    answer: "<span>1</span>",
    options: ["0", "1", "e", "none of these"],
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question: "If a=b, then b=a, &forall; a,b&isin;R this property is called.",
    answer: "<span>Symmetric property</span>",
    options: [
      "Symmetric property",
      "Reflexive property",
      "Transitive",
      "none of these",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "&forall; a,b&isin;R a&lt;b or a&gt;b or a=b is called.",
    answer: "<span>Trichotomy property</span>",
    options: [
      "Trichotomy property",
      "Reflexive property",
      "Transitive property",
      "none of these",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "ٰIn the redical &#8732;a the real number a is called__.",
    answer: "<span>radicand</span>",
    options: ["radicand", "index of radical", "radical", "none of these"],
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "In the redical &#8732;a the real number 4 is called__.",
    answer: "<span>index of radical</span>",
    options: ["radicand", "power", "radical", "index of radical"],
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "let a,b&isin;R and m,n be positive integers. then &#8732;ab=__.",
    answer: "<span>∜a∜b</span>",
    options: [
      "&#8732;a/&#8732;b",
      "&#8732;a&#8732;b",
      "&#8732;a+&#8732;b",
      "none of these",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question:
      "let a,b&isin;R and m,n be positive integers. Then a<sup>m</sup>.a<sup>n</sup>=___.",
    answer: "<span>a<sup>m+n</sup></span>",
    options: [
      "a<sup>m x n</sup>",
      "a<sup>m-n</sup>",
      "a<sup>m+n</sup>",
      "none of these",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question:
      "let a,b&isin;R and a&ne;0,b&ne;0 if a&lt;b then 1&#8725;a__1&#8725;b",
    answer: "<span>&gt;</span>",
    options: ["&lt;", "&gt;", "=", "none of these"],
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "let a,b&isin;R and a&ne;0 then a<sup>0</sup>=__?",
    answer: "<span>1</span>",
    options: ["0", "a", "1", "none of these"],
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "&#8730;-1=___?",
    answer: "<span>i</span>",
    options: ["i", "i<sup>2</sup>", "-1", "none of these"],
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "Real part of 2ab(i+i<sup>2</sup>) is.",
    answer: "<span>-2ab</span>",
    options: ["2ab", "-2ab", "-2abi", "2abi"],
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "Every real number is.",
    answer: "<span>a complex number</span>",
    options: [
      "a positive integer",
      "a rational number",
      "a negative number",
      "a complex number",
    ],
  },

  {
    numb: 16,
    question: "The value of i<sup>9</sup> is.",
    answer: "<span>i</span>",
    options: ["-1", "1", "-i", "i"],
  },
  {
    numb: 17,
    question: "Imaginary part of -i(3i+2) is.",
    answer: "<span>-2</span>",
    options: ["2", "-2", "3", "-3"],
  },
  {
    numb: 18,
    question: "A non-terminating, non-recurring decimal represents.",
    answer: "<span>an irrational number</span>",
    options: [
      "a natural number",
      "a rational number",
      "an irrational number",
      "a prime number",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 19,
    question:
      "Which of the following set have the closure property w.r.t addition.",
    answer: "<span>{0}</span>",
    options: ["{0}", "{0,-1}", "{0,1}", "none of these"],
  },
  {
    numb: 20,
    question: "If x,y,z&isin;R, z&lt;0, then x&lt;y&rArr;___.",
    answer: "<span>xz&gt;yz</span>",
    options: ["xz&lt;yz", "xz&gt;yz", "xz=yz", "none of these"],
  },
];

export const ch3mcqs = [
  {
  numb: 1,
  question: "A number written in the form a x 10<sup><i>n</i></sup>, where 1 &leq; a &lt;10 and <i>n</i> is an integer, is called___.",
  answer: "<span>scientific notation</span>",
  options: [
    "ordinary notation",
    "scientific notation",
    "pre-fixes",
    "none of these"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 2,
  question: "Correct conversion of ordinary number 0.000058 in scientific notation is.",
  answer: "<span>5.8 x 10<sup>-5</sup></span>",
  options: [
    "58 x 10<sup>6</sup>",
    "58 x 10<sup>-6</sup>",
    "5.8 x 10<sup>5</sup>",
    "5.8 x 10<sup>-5</sup>"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 3,
  question: "If log<sub>a</sub>y = x then.",
  answer: "<span>a<sup>x</sup> = y</span>",
  options: [
    "a<sup>y</sup> = x",
    "a<sup>x</sup> = y",
    "x<sup>a</sup> = y",
    "y<sup>x</sup> = a"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 4,
  question: "3<sup>2</sup> = 9 is equivalent to___.",
  answer: "<span>log<sub>3</sub>9 = 2</span>",
  options: [
    "log<sub>2</sub>9 = 3",
    "log<sub>3</sub>2 = 9",
    "log<sub>3</sub>9 = 2",
    "log<sub>9</sub>3 = 2"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 5,
  question: "log<sub>2</sub>16 =4 is equivalent to___.",
  answer: "<span>2<sup>4</sup> = 16</span>",
  options: [
    "16<sup>4</sup> = 2",
    "2<sup>16</sup> = 4",
    "2<sup>4</sup> = 16",
    "none of these"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 6,
  question: "The logarithm of unity to any base is.",
  answer: "<span>0</span>",
  options: [
    "1",
    "<i>e</i>",
    "10",
    "0"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 7,
  question: "The logarithm of any number to itself as base is.",
  answer: "<span>1</span>",
  options: [
    "1",
    "0",
    "<i>e</i>",
    "10"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 8,
  question: "log<i>e</i> = ...., where <i>e</i> ",
  answer: "<span>0.4343</span>",
  options: [
    "0",
    "0.4343",
    "&infin;",
    "1"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 9,
  question: "The value of log(p/q) is___.",
  answer: "<span>log p - log q</span>",
  options: [
    "log p / log q",
    "log p + log q",
    "log p - log q",
    "log q - log p"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 10,
  question: "log (<i>m</i><sup><i>n</i></sup>) can be written as___.",
  answer: "<span><i>n</i> log <i>m</i></span>",
  options: [
    "log (<i>m</i>)<sup><i>n</i></sup>",
    "<i>m</i> log <i>n</i>",
    "<i>n</i> log <i>m</i>",
    "log (<i>m</i><i>n</i>)"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 11,
  question: "log<sub><i>b</i></sub> <i>a</i> x log<sub><i>c</i></sub> <i>b</i> can be written as___.",
  answer: "<span>log<sub><i>c</i></sub> <i>a</i></span>",
  options: [
    "log<sub><i>a</i></sub> <i>c</i>",
    "log<sub><i>c</i></sub> <i>a</i>",
    "log<sub><i>a</i></sub> <i>b</i>",
    "log<sub><i>b</i></sub> <i>c</i>"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 12,
  question: "log<sub><i>a</i></sub> <i>n</i> will be equal to___.",
  answer: "<span>log<sub><i>b</i></sub> <i>n</i> / log<sub><i>b</i></sub> <i>a</i></span>",
  options: [
    "log<sub><i>b</i></sub> <i>n</i> / log<sub><i>a</i></sub> <i>c</i>",
    "log<sub><i>b</i></sub> <i>n</i> / log<sub><i>b</i></sub> <i>a</i>",
    "log<sub><i>b</i></sub> <i>n</i> / log<sub><i>a</i></sub> <i>c</i>",
    "log<sub><i>a</i></sub> <i>b</i> / log<sub><i>b</i></sub> <i>a</i>"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 13,
  question: "Value of log<sub>2</sub> 3 x log<sub>3</sub> 8 is.",
  answer: "<span>3</span>",
  options: [
    "2",
    "4",
    "16",
    "8"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 14,
  question: "If log<sub>3</sub> x = 4 then value of x is.",
  answer: "<span>81</span>",
  options: [
    "64",
    "81",
    "12",
    "none of these"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 15,
  question: "If log 2 = 0.3010, log 3 = 0.4771 then value of log 16/15 is.",
  answer: "<span>0.0279</span>",
  options: [
    "0.00279",
    "2.79",
    "0.279",
    "0.0279"
  ]
}
]

export const ch4mcqs = [
  {
  numb: 1,
  question: "When we apply operations of addition and substraction to algebraic terms, we get___.",
  answer: "<span>Algeraic expression</span>",
  options: [
    "Polynomial",
    "Algeraic expression",
    "Algebraic equation",
    "Algebraic sentence"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 2,
  question: "4x + 3y - 2 is an algebraic___.",
  answer: "<span>Algeraic expression</span>",
  options: [
    "Polynomial",
    "Algeraic expression",
    "Algebraic equation",
    "Algebraic sentence"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 3,
  question: "The degree of polynomial 2x<sup>5</sup>y<sup>3</sup> + x<sup>2</sup>y<sup>2</sup> is.",
  answer: "<span>8</span>",
  options: [
    "8",
    "5",
    "3",
    "2"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 4,
  question: "a<sup>3</sup> + b<sup>3</sup> is equal to___.",
  answer: "<span>(a + b)(a<sup>2</sup> - ab + b<sup>2</sup>)</span>",
  options: [
    "(a - b)(a<sup>2</sup> + ab + b<sup>2</sup>)",
    "(a + b)(a<sup>2</sup> - ab + b<sup>2</sup>)",
    "(a - b)(a<sup>2</sup> - ab + b<sup>2</sup>)",
    "(a - b)(a<sup>2</sup> + ab - b<sup>2</sup>)"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 5,
  question: "a<sup>3</sup> - b<sup>3</sup> is equal to___.",
  answer: "<span>(a - b)(a<sup>2</sup> + ab + b<sup>2</sup>)</span>",
  options: [
    "(a - b)(a<sup>2</sup> + ab + b<sup>2</sup>)",
    "(a + b)(a<sup>2</sup> - ab + b<sup>2</sup>)",
    "(a - b)(a<sup>2</sup> - ab + b<sup>2</sup>)",
    "(a - b)(a<sup>2</sup> + ab - b<sup>2</sup>)"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 6,
  question: "(3 + &radic;2)(3 - &radic;2) is equal to.",
  answer: "<span>7</span>",
  options: [
    "7",
    "-7",
    "1",
    "-1"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 7,
  question: "Conjugate of surd a + &radic;b is.",
  answer: "<span>a - √b</span>",
  options: [
    "-a + &radic;b",
    "a - &radic;b",
    "&radic;a + &radic;b",
    "&radic;a - &radic;b"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 8,
  question: "(&radic;a - &radic;b)(&radic;a + &radic;b) is equal to ___.",
  answer: "<span>a - b</span>",
  options: [
    "a<sup>2</sup> - b<sup>2</sup>",
    "a<sup>2</sup> + b<sup>2</sup>",
    "a - b",
    "a + b"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 9,
  question: "a<sup>2</sup> - b<sup>2</sup> &#8725; a<sup>2</sup> + b<sup>2</sup> is equal to___.",
  answer: "<span>a - b</span>",
  options: [
    "(a - b)<sup>2</sup>",
    "(a + b)<sup>2</sup>",
    "a + b",
    "a - b"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 10,
  question: "Order of surd &#8731;x is.",
  answer: "<span>3</span>",
  options: [
    "1 &#8725; 2",
    "1 &#8725; 3",
    "3",
    "none of these"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 11,
  question: "x<sup>2</sup> - 4 = .....",
  answer: "<span>(x - 2)(x + 2)</span>",
  options: [
    "2",
    "(x - 2)(x + 2)",
    "(x<sup>2</sup> - 2)(x<sup>2</sup> + 2)",
    "(x<sup>2</sup> - 2)<sup>2</sup>"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 12,
  question: "1 &#8725; (a - b) - 1 &#8725; (a + b) is equal to.",
  answer: "<span>2b ∕ a<sup>2</sup> - b<sup>2</sup></span>",
  options: [
    "2a &#8725; a<sup>2</sup> - b<sup>2</sup>",
    "2b &#8725; a<sup>2</sup> - b<sup>2</sup>",
    "-2a &#8725; a<sup>2</sup> - b<sup>2</sup>",
    "-2b &#8725; a<sup>2</sup> - b<sup>2</sup>"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 13,
  question: "1 &#8725; (2 - &radic;3) is equal to.",
  answer: "<span>2 + √3</span>",
  options: [
    "-2 - &radic;3",
    "2 + &radic;3",
    "2 - &radic;3",
    "-2 + &radic;3"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 14,
  question: "If a + b + c = 6 and a<sup>2</sup> + b<sup>2</sup> + c<sup>2</sup> = 24 then the value of ab + bc + ca is.",
  answer: "<span>6</span>",
  options: [
    "4",
    "6",
    "30",
    "none of these"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 15,
  question: "if x - 1 &#8725; x = 4 then x<sup>3</sup> - 1 &#8725; x<sup>3</sup> is equal to.",
  answer: "<span>76</span>",
  options: [
    "76",
    "64",
    "52",
    "none of these"
  ]
}
]

export const ch5mcqs = [
  {
  numb: 1,
  question: "6x<sup>4</sup> - 96 is equal to.",
  answer: "<span>6(x - 2)(x + 2)(x<sup>2</sup> + 4)</sup>",
  options: [
    "6(x<sup>2</sup> - 4)(x<sup>2</sup> + 4)",
    "6(x - 2)(x + 2)(x<sup>2</sup> + 4)",
    "(x - 2)(x + 2)(x<sup>2</sup> + 4)",
    "none of these"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 2,
  question: "If a polynomial p(x) is divided by a linear divisor (x - a), then the remainder is___.",
  answer: "<span>p(a)</span>",
  options: [
    "(x - a)",
    "q(x)",
    "q(a)",
    "p(a)"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 3,
  question: "The polynomial (x - a) is a factor of the polynomial p(x) if and only if___.",
  answer: "<span>p(a) = 0</span>",
  options: [
    "p(a) = 0",
    "a = 0",
    "p(x) = 0",
    "none of these"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 4,
  question: "__is the remainder when 9x<sup>2</sup> - 6x + 2 is divided by x - 3",
  answer: "<span>64</span>",
  options: [
    "101",
    "65",
    "81",
    "none of these"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 5,
  question: "Value of k is___if the expression x<sup>3</sup> + kx<sup>2</sup> +3x - 4 leaves a remainder of -2 when divided by x + 2",
  answer: "<span>4</span>",
  options: [
    "4",
    "5",
    "0",
    "20"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 6,
  question: "The polynomial (x - a) is a___of the polynomial p(x) if and only if p(a) = 0.",
  answer: "<span>factor</span>",
  options: [
    "remainder",
    "quotient",
    "zero",
    "factor"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 7,
  question: "The factors of x<sup>2</sup> - 5x + 6 are....",
  answer: "<span>x - 2, x - 3</span>",
  options: [
    "x - 2, x - 3",
    "x + 1, x - 6",
    "x + 6, x - 1",
    "x + 2, x + 3"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 8,
  question: "Factors of 8x<sup>3</sup> + 27y<sup>3</sup> are....",
  answer: "<span>(2x + 3y),(4x<sup>2</sup> - 6xy + 9y<sup>2</sup>)</span>",
  options: [
    "(2x + 3y),(4x<sup>2</sup> + 9y<sup>2</sup>)",
    "(2x - 3y),(4x<sup>2</sup> - 9y<sup>2</sup>)",
    "(2x + 3y),(4x<sup>2</sup> - 6xy + 9y<sup>2</sup>)",
    "(2x - 3y),(4x<sup>2</sup> + 6xy + 9y<sup>2</sup>)"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 9,
  question: "Factors of 3x<sup>2</sup> - x - 2 are....",
  answer: "<span>(x - 1), (3x + 2)</span>",
  options: [
    "(x + 1), (3x - 2)",
    "(x + 1), (3x + 2)",
    "(x - 1), (3x - 2)",
    "(x - 1), (3x + 2)"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 10,
  question: "Factors of a<sup>4</sup> - 4b<sup>4</sup> are....",
  answer: "<span>(a<sup>2</sup> - 2b<sup>2</sup>), (a<sup>2</sup> + 2b<sup>2</sup>)</span>",
  options: [
    "(a - b), (a + b), (a<sup>2</sup> + 4b<sup>2</sup>)",
    "(a - b), (a + b), (a<sup>2</sup> - 4b<sup>2</sup>)",
    "(a<sup>2</sup> - 2b<sup>2</sup>), (a<sup>2</sup> + 2b<sup>2</sup>)",
    "(a - 2b), (a<sup>2</sup> + 2b<sup>2</sup>)"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 11,
  question: "What will be added to complete the square of 9a<sup>2</sup> - 12ab?",
  answer: "<span>4b<sup>2</sup></span>",
  options: [
    "-16b<sup>2</sup>",
    "16b<sup>2</sup>",
    "-4b<sup>2</sup>",
    "4b<sup>2</sup>"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 12,
  question: "Find m so that  x<sup>2</sup> + 4x + m is a complete square....",
  answer: "<span>4</span>",
  options: [
    "8",
    "-8",
    "4",
    "16"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 13,
  question: "Factors of 5x<sup>2</sup> - 17xy - 12y<sup>2</sup> are....",
  answer: "<span>(x - 4y), (5x + 3y)</span>",
  options: [
    "(x + 4y), (5x + 3y)",
    "(x - 4y), (5x - 3y)",
    "(x - 4y), (5x + 3y)",
    "(5x - 4y), (x + 3y)"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 14,
  question: "a<sub>0</sub>x<sup>n</sup> + a<sub>1</sub>x<sup>n-1</sup> + ... + a<sub>n-1</sub>x + a<sub>n</sub> is a polynomial of degree___with integral coefficients.",
  answer: "<span>n</span>",
  options: [
    "n-1",
    "n+1",
    "n",
    "none of these"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 15,
  question: "Polynomial p(x) of degree 3 that has 2, -1, and 3 as zeros is.",
  answer: "<span>p(x) = (x - 2)(x + 1)(x - 3)</span>",
  options: [
    "p(x) = (x - 2)(x - 1)(x - 3)",
    "p(x) = (x + 2)(x - 1)(x + 3)",
    "p(x) = (x + 2)(x + 1)(x + 3)",
    "p(x) = (x - 2)(x + 1)(x - 3)"
  ]
}
]

export const ch6mcqs = [
  {
  numb: 1,
  question: "H.C.F of the polynomials x<sup>2</sup> - 4, x<sup>2</sup> + 4x + 4, 2x<sup>2</sup> + x - 6 is.",
  answer: "(x + 2)",
  options: [
    "(x + 2)<sup>2</sup>",
    "(x - 2)",
    "(x + 2)(x - 2)",
    "(x + 2)"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 2,
  question: "if p(x) and q(x) are two polynomials then relation between H.C.F and L.C.M is.",
  answer: "<span>L.C.M x H.C.F = p(x) x q(x)</span>",
  options: [
    "L.C.M x p(x) = H.C.F x q(x)",
    "L.C.M x q(x) = H.C.F x p(x)",
    "L.C.M x p(x) = H.C.F",
    "L.C.M x H.C.F = p(x) x q(x)"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 3,
  question: "L.C.M of x<sup>2</sup> - 25x + 100 and x<sup>2</sup> - x - 20 is.",
  answer: "<span>(x - 5)(x - 20)(x + 4)</span>",
  options: [
    "(x + 5)(x + 20)(x - 4)",
    "(x - 5)(x - 20)(x + 4)",
    "(x - 5)(x + 4)",
    "none of these"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 4,
  question: "Square of the expression 4x<sup>2</sup> - 12x + 9 is....",
  answer: "<span>&PlusMinus;(2x - 3)</span>",
  options: [
    "&PlusMinus;(2x - 3)",
    "(2x - 3)",
    "&PlusMinus;(2x + 3)",
    "none of these"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 5,
  question: "H.C.F of p<sup>3</sup>q - pq<sup>3</sup> and p<sup>5</sup>q<sup>2</sup> - p<sup>2</sup>q<sup>5</sup> is....",
  answer: "<span>pq(p - q)</span>",
  options: [
    "pq(p<sup>2</sup> - q<sup>2</sup>)",
    "pq(p - q)",
    "p<sup>2</sup>q<sup>2</sup>(p - q)",
    "pq(p<sup>3</sup> - q<sup>3</sup>)"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 6,
  question: "H.C.F of 5x<sup>2</sup>y<sup>2</sup> and 20x<sup>3</sup>y<sup>3</sup> is....",
  answer: "<span>5x<sup>2</sup>y<sup>2</sup></span>",
  options: [
    "5x<sup>2</sup>y<sup>2</sup>",
    "20x<sup>3</sup>y<sup>3</sup>",
    "100x<sup>5</sup>y<sup>5</sup>",
    "5xy"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 7,
  question: "H.C.F of x - 2 and x<sup>2</sup> + x - 6 is....",
  answer: "<span>x - 2</span>",
  options: [
    "x<sup>2</sup> + x - 6",
    "x + 3",
    "x - 2",
    "x + 2"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 8,
  question: "H.C.F of a<sup>3</sup> + b<sup>3</sup> and a<sup>2</sup> - ab + b<sup>2</sup> is....",
  answer: "<span>a<sup>2</sup> - ab + b<sup>2</sup></span>",
  options: [
    "a + b",
    "a<sup>2</sup> - ab + b<sup>2</sup>",
    "(a - b)<sup>2</sup>",
    "a<sup>2</sup> + b<sup>2</sup>"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 9,
  question: "H.C.F of x<sup>2</sup> - 5x + 6 is x<sup>2</sup> - x - 6 is...",
  answer: "<span>x - 3</span>",
  options: [
    "x - 3",
    "x + 2",
    "x<sup>2</sup> - 4",
    "x - 2"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 10,
  question: "H.C.F of a<sup>2</sup> - b<sup>2</sup> and a<sup>3</sup> - b<sup>3</sup> is.",
  answer: "<span>a - b</span>",
  options: [
    "a + b",
    "a - b",
    "a<sup>2</sup> + ab + b<sup>2</sup>",
    "a<sup>2</sup> - ab + b<sup>2</sup>"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 11,
  question: "H.C.F of x<sup>2</sup> + 3x + 2, x<sup>2</sup> + 4x + 3, and x<sup>2</sup> + 5x + 4 is..",
  answer: "<span>x + 1</span>",
  options: [
    "(x + 4)(x + 1)",
    "x + 3",
    "(x + 1)(x + 2)",
    "x + 1"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 12,
  question: "L.C.M of 15x<sup>2</sup>, 45xy and 30xyz is....",
  answer: "<span>90x<sup>2</sup>yz</span>",
  options: [
    "90xyz",
    "90x<sup>2</sup>yz",
    "15xyz",
    "15x<sup>2</sup>yz"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 13,
  question: "L.C.M of a<sup>2</sup> + b<sup>2</sup> and a<sup>4</sup> - b<sup>4</sup> is....",
  answer: "<span></span>",
  options: [
    "a<sup>2</sup> + b<sup>2</sup>",
    "a<sup>2</sup> - b<sup>2</sup>",
    "a<sup>4</sup> - b<sup>4</sup>",
    "a - b"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 14,
  question: "The product of two algebraic expressions is equal to the....of their H.C.F and L.C.M.",
  answer: "<span>Product</span>",
  options: [
    "Sum",
    "Difference",
    "Product",
    "Quotient"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 15,
  question: "What should be added to complete the square of x<sup>4</sup> + 64 ?",
  answer: "<span>16x<sup>2</sup></span>",
  options: [
    "8x<sup>2</sup>",
    "-8x<sup>2</sup>",
    "16x<sup>2</sup>",
    "4x<sup>2</sup>"
  ]
}
]

export const ch7mcqs = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question:
      "A linear equation in one variable x is an equation of the form ax + b = 0 where a,b &isin; R and___.",
    answer: "<span>a &NotEqual; 0</span>",
    options: [
      "b &NotEqual; 0",
      "a = 0, b &NotEqual; 0",
      "a &NotEqual; 0",
      "b = 0",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Solution of the equation &radic;(2x - 3) - 7 = 0 is.",
    answer: "<span>26</span>",
    options: ["52", "50", "26", "104"],
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "If a,b &isin; R, then",
    answer: "<span>|a| &ge; 0</span>",
    options: ["|a| &gt; 0", "|a| &ge; 0", "|a| &equals; 0", "|a| &le; 0"],
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question: "If a,b &isin; R, then",
    answer: "<span>|-a| &equals; |a|</span>",
    options: [
      "|-a| &equals; -|a|",
      "|-a| &equals; |-a|",
      "|-a| &equals; |a|",
      "none of these",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question: "The solution set of the equation |8x - 3| = |4x + 5| is....",
    answer: "<span>x = {2, -1/6}</span>",
    options: ["x = {2}", "x = {-2, 1/6}", "x = {2, -1/6}", "x = {-1/6}"],
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question:
      "For any a,b &isin; R, one and only one of the statements a &lt; b, a &equals; b, a &gt; b is true. This property of real numbers is called.",
    answer: "<span>Law of trichotomy</span>",
    options: [
      "Symmetric property",
      "Transitive property",
      "Law of trichotomy",
      "none of these",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question:
      "The solution set of the inequality 4x - 1 &le; 3 &le; 7 + 2x is....",
    answer: "<span>solution set = {x | -2 &le; x &le; 1}</span>",
    options: [
      "{x | 2 &le; x &le; 1}",
      "{x | -2 &le; x &le; 1}",
      "{x | x &le; 1}",
      "none of these",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question:
      "Which of the following is the solution of the inequality 3 - 4x &le; 11 ?",
    answer: "<span>None of these</span>",
    options: ["-8", "-2", "-14/4", "None of these"],
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question:
      "A statement involving any of the symbols &lt;, &gt;, &le; or &ge; is called....",
    answer: "<span>inequality</span>",
    options: ["equation", "identity", "inequality", "linear equation"],
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question:
      "x &equals; .... is a solution of the inequality -2 &lt; x &lt; 3/2.",
    answer: "<span>0</span>",
    options: ["-5", "3", "0", "3/2"],
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "If x is no larger than 10, then ....",
    answer: "<span>x &le; 10</span>",
    options: ["x &ge; 8", "x &le; 10", "x &lt; 10", "x &gt; 10"],
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question:
      "If the capacity c of an elevator is at most 1600 pounds, then....",
    answer: "<span>c &le; 1600</span>",
    options: ["c &lt; 1600", "c &ge; 1600", "c &le; 1600", "c &gt; 1600"],
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "x &equals; 0 is the solution of the inequality....",
    answer: "<span>x - 2 &lt; 0</span>",
    options: ["x &gt; 0", "3x + 5 &lt; 0", "x + 2 &lt; 0", "x - 2 &lt; 0"],
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "The equation 3x - 5 &equals; 7 - x is a....equation.",
    answer: "<span>linear</span>",
    options: ["quadratic", "linear", "cubic", "none of these"],
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question:
      "The solution set of 9 - 7x &gt; 19 - 2x where x &isin; R is.....",
    answer: "<span></span>",
    options: [
      "{x | x &gt; 2}",
      "{x | x &lt; -2}",
      "{x | x &gt; -2}",
      "None of these",
    ],
  },
];

export const ch8mcqs = [
  {
  numb: 1,
  question: "If (x - 1, y + 1) &equals; (0, 0), then (x, y) is:",
  answer: "<span>(1, -1)</span>",
  options: [
    "(1, -1)",
    "(-1, 1)",
    "(1, 1)",
    "(-1, -1)"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 2,
  question: "If (x, 0) &equals; (0, y), then (x, y) is:",
  answer: "<span>(0, 0)</span>",
  options: [
    "(0, 1)",
    "(1, 0)",
    "(0, 0)",
    "(1, 1)"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 3,
  question: "Point (2, -3) lies in....quadrant.",
  answer: "<span>IV</span>",
  options: [
    "I",
    "II",
    "III",
    "IV"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 4,
  question: "Point (-3, -3) lies in....quadrant.",
  answer: "<span>III</span>",
  options: [
    "I",
    "II",
    "III",
    "IV"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 5,
  question: "If y &equals; 2x + 1, x &equals; 2 then y is....",
  answer: "<span>5</span>",
  options: [
    "4",
    "3",
    "5",
    "2"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 6,
  question: "Which ordered pair satisfies the equation y = 2x ?",
  answer: "<span>(1, 2)</span>",
  options: [
    "(2, 1)",
    "(2, 2)",
    "(1, 2)",
    "(0, 1)"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 7,
  question: "The point R(0, 1) lies on the....",
  answer: "<span>y-axis</span>",
  options: [
    "x-axis",
    "y-axis",
    "z-axis",
    "None of these"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 8,
  question: "The point P(1, 1) lies on the line.....",
  answer: "<span>3x - y &equals; 2</span>",
  options: [
    "x + y &equals; 0",
    "x + 2y &equals; 0",
    "3x - y &equals; 2",
    "x - 3y &equals; 0"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 9,
  question: "The graph of x &equals; -2 is a.....",
  answer: "<span>vertical line</span>",
  options: [
    "horizontal line",
    "vertical line",
    "xy-plane",
    "xz-plane"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 10,
  question: "3 - y &equals; is a...",
  answer: "<span>horizontal line</span>",
  options: [
    "horizontal line",
    "vertical line",
    "xy-plane",
    "xz-plane"
  ]
},
]

export const ch9mcqs = [
  {
  numb: 1,
  question: "Distance formula is....",
  answer: "<span>d = &radic;(|x<sub>2</sub> - x<sub>1</sub>|<sup>2</sup> + |y<sub>2</sub> - y<sub>1</sub>|<sup>2</sup>)</span>",
  options: [
    "d = &radic;(|x<sub>2</sub> - x<sub>1</sub>|<sup>2</sup> + |y<sub>2</sub> - y<sub>1</sub>|<sup>2</sup>)",
    "d = &radic;(|x<sub>2</sub> - x<sub>1</sub>|<sup>2</sup> - |y<sub>2</sub> - y<sub>1</sub>|<sup>2</sup>)",
    "d = &radic;(|x<sub>2</sub> - y<sub>1</sub>|<sup>2</sup> + |y<sub>2</sub> - x<sub>1</sub>|<sup>2</sup>)",
    "None of these"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 2,
  question: "Distance between the points U(0, 2) and V(-3, 0) is....",
  answer: "<span>&radic;13</span>",
  options: [
    "&radic;5",
    "&radic;13",
    "5",
    "&radic;23"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 3,
  question: "Distance between points (0, 0) and (1, 1) is....",
  answer: "<span>&radic;2</span>",
  options: [
    "0",
    "1",
    "2",
    "&radic;2"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 4,
  question: "Distance between points (1, 0) and (0, 1) is....",
  answer: "<span>&radic;2</span>",
  options: [
    "0",
    "1",
    "&radic;2",
    "2"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 5,
  question: "The mid point of the line segment joining A(2, 5) and B(-1,1) is...",
  answer: "<span>R(1/2, 3)</span>",
  options: [
    "R(3/2, 2)",
    "R(1/2, 3)",
    "R(2, 1)",
    "R(1, 2)"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 6,
  question: "Mid-point of the points (2, 2) and (0, 0) is...",
  answer: "<span>(1, 1)</span>",
  options: [
    "(1, 1)",
    "(1, 0)",
    "(0, 1)",
    "(-1, -1)"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 7,
  question: "Mid-point of the points (2, -2) and (-2, 2) is...",
  answer: "<span>(0, 0)</span>",
  options: [
    "(2, 2)",
    "(-2, -2)",
    "(0, 0)",
    "(1, 1)"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 8,
  question: "A triangle having two sides equal is called....",
  answer: "<span>Equilateral</span>",
  options: [
    "Isosceles",
    "Scalene",
    "Equilateral",
    "None of these"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 9,
  question: "A triangle having two sides different is called....",
  answer: "<span>Scalene</span>",
  options: [
    "Isosceles",
    "Scalene",
    "Equilateral",
    "None of these"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 10,
  question: "Each side of a triangle has....collinear vertices.",
  answer: "<span>two</span>",
  options: [
    "three",
    "two",
    "one",
    "None of these"
  ]
},
]

export const ch10mcqs = [
  {
  numb: 1,
  question: "In a triangle, there can be only....right angle.",
  answer: "<span>one</span>",
  options: [
    "two",
    "one",
    "three",
    "four"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 2,
  question: "Three points are said to be collinear, if they lie on....",
  answer: "<span>same line</span>",
  options: [
    "same sides",
    "same line",
    "same angle",
    "None of these"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 3,
  question: "Two parallel lines intersect at....point",
  answer: "<span>None of these</span>",
  options: [
    "one",
    "two",
    "many points",
    "None of these"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 4,
  question: "Two can lines intersect at....point",
  answer: "<span>one</span>",
  options: [
    "one",
    "two",
    "many points",
    "None of these"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 5,
  question: "A triangle of congruent sides has....angles.",
  answer: "<span>congruent</span>",
  options: [
    "non-congruent",
    "equals",
    "congruent",
    "None of these"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 6,
  question: "If the bisector of an angle of a triangle bisects the side opposite to it, then the triangle is___.",
  answer: "<span>isosceles</span>",
  options: [
    "equilateral",
    "right angle",
    "isosceles",
    "none of these"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 7,
  question: "An equilaterl triangle is an___tirangle.",
  answer: "<span>equiangular</span>",
  options: [
    "acute triangle",
    "isosceles",
    "right angle",
    "equiangular"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 8,
  question: "If perpendiculars from two vertices of a triangle to the opposite sides are congruent, then the triangle is___.",
  answer: "<span>isosceles</span>",
  options: [
    "acute triangle",
    "isosceles",
    "right angle",
    "equiangular"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 9,
  question: "In a isosceles triangle____angles are equal in measure.",
  answer: "<span>two</span>",
  options: [
    "two",
    "three",
    "all",
    "none of these"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 10,
  question: "A tirangle each of whose angles measures less than 90 degrees is called___triangle.",
  answer: "<span>acute triangle</span>",
  options: [
    "isosceles",
    "acute triangle",
    "right angle",
    "equiangular"
  ]
},
]